outdoorchannel.com 2019-03-22

# Privacy Policy | Outdoor Channel

## Privacy Policy

The Outdoor Channel, Inc. (“ ** _Outdoor Channel_** ”) respects the privacy of others. This PRIVACY POLICY (this “ ** _Privacy Policy_** ”) is intended to explain Outdoor Channel’s privacy practices with respect to the OutdoorChannel.com website (together with its pages and features, the “ ** _Site_** ”). This Privacy Policy is also intended to provide you and any person helping you visit, access or use the Site (collectively, “ ** _you_** ” or “ ** _your_** ”) with an overview of the following:

  * the type of information about you Outdoor Channel collects through the Site;

  * how Outdoor Channel collects such information;

  * how Outdoor Channel uses such information;

  * who will have access to such information; and

  * Outdoor Channel’s security measures for protecting such information.

THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES TO INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE SITE. CAREFULLY READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN ITS ENTIRETY.

BY VISITING, ACCESSING, REGISTERING WITH OR USING THE SITE, YOU ARE AUTOMATICALLY ACCEPTING AND AGREEING TO THE MOST-RECENT VERSION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AS WELL AS THE SITE’S [TERMS OF SERVICE](http://www.outdoorchannel.com/termsofuse), AND YOUR CONTINUING VISIT, ACCESS, REGISTRATION WITH OR USE OF THE SITE REAFFIRMS YOUR ACCEPTANCE AND AGREEMENT IN EACH INSTANCE.

As used herein, the term “ ** _personal information_** ” means information that would allow someone to specifically identify you or contact you physically or online (e.g., your name, physical address, telephone number, email address); and the term “ ** _non-personal information_** ” means any information other than personal information that Outdoor Channel may collect from you.

### **1\. A SPECIAL NOTE ABOUT MINORS.**

The Site is a general audience website intended for use by adults. The Site is not designed or intended to attract, and is not directed to, children under eighteen (18) years of age, let alone children under thirteen (13) years of age. Outdoor Channel does not collect personal information through the Site from any person it actually knows to be under thirteen (13) years of age. If Outdoor Channel obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information through the Site from a person under thirteen (13) years of age, then it will use reasonable efforts to refrain from further using such personal information or maintaining it in retrievable form.

Furthermore, if you are under eighteen (18) years of age, then you (or your parent or legal guardian) may at any time request that Outdoor Channel remove content or information about you that is posted on the Site. Please submit any such request (“ ** _Request for Removal of Minor Information_** ”) to [info@outdoorchannel.com](mailto:info@outdoorchannel.com), with a subject line of “Removal of Minor Information.”

For each Request for Removal of Minor Information, please state “Removal of Minor Information” in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:

  1. the nature of your request;

  2. the identity of the content or information to be removed;

  3. the location on content or information on the Site (e.g., providing the URL for the specific web page the content or information is found on);

  4. that the request is related to the “Removal of Minor Information;”

  5. your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address; and

  6. whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

Outdoor Channel is not responsible for failing to comply with any Request for Removal of Minor Information that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled or incorrectly sent.

PLEASE NOTE THAT THE AFOREMENTIONED REMOVAL DOES NOT ENSURE COMPLETE OR COMPREHENSIVE REMOVAL OF SUCH CONTENT OR INFORMATION POSTED ON THE SITE.

Also, please note that Outdoor Channel is not required to erase or otherwise eliminate, or to enable erasure or elimination of, such content or information in certain circumstances, such as, for example, when an international, federal, state, or local law, rule or regulation requires Outdoor Channel to maintain the content or information; when the content or information is stored on or posted to the Site by a third party other than you (including any content or information posted by you that was stored, republished or reposted by the third party); when Outdoor Channel anonymizes the content or information, so that you cannot be individually identified; when you do not follow the aforementioned instructions for requesting the removal of the content or information; and when you have received compensation or other consideration for providing the content or information.

The foregoing is a description of Outdoor Channel’s voluntary practices concerning the collection of personal information through the Site from certain minors, and is not intended to be an admission that Outdoor Channel is subject to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, the Federal Trade Commission’s Children’s Online Privacy Protection Rule(s), or any similar international, federal, state, or local laws, rules, or regulations.

### **2\. CATEGORIES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED.**

Outdoor Channel may collect personal and non-personal information about you through the Site. The categories of such information might include:

  * Your name (first, last and/or middle) and unique identifiers (e.g., username);

  * Your contact information (e.g., mailing address, email address, telephone number);

  * Your electronic signature;

  * Information related to your inquires about possible advertising opportunities with Outdoor Channel and/or one or more of its affiliated companies (e.g., brands, media, markets);

  * Information related to your inquiries about possible employment with Outdoor Channel and/or one or more of its affiliated companies (e.g., name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, salary requirements, interests, resume);

  * Your computer, mobile device, and/or browser information (e.g., IP address, mobile device ID information, operating system, connection speed, bandwidth, browser type, referring/exit web pages, web page requests, cookie information, hardware attributes, software attributes);

  * Third-party website, network, platform, server and/or application information (e.g., Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, Instagram);

  * Usage activity concerning your interactions with the Site and/or third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications accessed through the Site (e.g., how you accessed the Site, where you go when you leave the Site, number of clicks on a page or feature, amount of time spent on the Site or a page or feature, identity of third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers and applications accessed through the Site);

  * Usage activity concerning products and services provided to or accessed by you on or through the Site (e.g., viewing habits, viewing preferences, viewing history, title selections, favorites, streams, downloads, demographics and closed captioning selections);

  * Your transactional information (e.g., offers, orders, pricing, payments, purchaser, seller, item information, shipping terms, comments, ratings, feedback and instant messages and/or other communications made within or through the Site);

  * Your hobbies and other leisure activities and interests;

  * Your television subscription information and preferences (e.g., television service providers, subscription rates, programs and genre preferences, viewing habits);

  * Information about third parties that you refer to Outdoor Channel (e.g., name, email and/or other contact information, relationship);

  * Statements or content (e.g., comments, videos, photographs, images), and information about such statements or content, which you submit or publish on or through the Site, or which are accessed via your public or linked social media pages (e.g., Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, Instagram);

  * Your name associated with your mobile device;

  * Your telephone number associated with your mobile device;

  * Your geolocation; and/or

  * Your mobile device ID information.

### **3\. HOW INFORMATION IS COLLECTED.**

Outdoor Channel might collect personal and non-personal information from you when you visit, access or use the Site; when you subscribe to newsletters on or through the Site; when you register for, order, purchase or subscribe to any products and/or services through the Site; when you allow the Site to access, upload, download, import or export content found on or through, or to otherwise interact with, your computer or mobile device (or any other device you may use to visit, access or use the Site) or online accounts with third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications (e.g., your online social media accounts, your cloud drives and servers, your mobile device service provider); or whenever Outdoor Channel asks you for such information, such as, for example, when you answer an online survey or questionnaire.

In addition, if you or a third party sends Outdoor Channel a comment, message or other communication (such as, by way of example only, email, letter, fax, phone call, or voice message) about you or your activities on or through the Site, then Outdoor Channel may collect any personal or non-personal information provided therein or therewith.

Finally, Outdoor Channel might use various tracking, data aggregation and/or data analysis technologies, including, for example, the following:

  * Cookies, which are small data files (e.g., text files) stored on the browser or device you use to view a website or message. They may help store user preferences and activity, and may allow a website to recognize a particular browser or device. There are several types of cookies, including, for example, browser cookies, session cookies, and persistent cookies. Cookies may record information you access on one page of a website to simplify subsequent interaction with that website, or to help streamline your transactions on related pages of that website. Most major browsers are set up so that they will initially accept cookies, but you might be able to adjust your browser’s or device’s preferences to issue you an alert when a cookie is downloaded, or to block, reject, disable, delete or manage the use of some or all cookies on your browser or device.

  * Flash cookies, which are cookies written using Adobe Flash, and which may be permanently stored on your device. Like regular cookies, Flash cookies may help store user preferences and activity, and may allow a website to recognize a particular browser or device. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings that are used for regular cookies.

  * Web beacons, which are pieces of code embedded in a website or email to monitor your activity on the website or your opening of the email, and which can pass along information such as the IP address of the computer or device you use to view the website or open the email, the URL page on which the web beacon is located, the type of browser that was used to access the website, and previously set cookie values. Web beacons are sometimes used to collect advertising data, such as counting page views, promotion views or advertising responses. Disabling your computer’s, device’s or browser’s cookies may prevent some web beacons from tracking or recording certain information about your activities.

  * Scripts, which are pieces of code embedded in a website to define how the website behaves in response to certain key or click requests sent by the user. Scripts are sometimes used to collect information about the user’s interactions with the website, such as the links the user clicks on. Scripts are often times temporarily downloaded to the user’s computer or device from the website server, active only while the user is connected to the Site, and deactivated or deleted when the user disconnects from the Site.

  * Analytic tools and services, which are sometimes offered by third parties, and which track, measure and/or generate information about a website’s or program’s traffic, sales, audience and similar information, and which may be used for various reasons, such as, for example, content ratings research, and conversion tracking.

Please be advised that if you choose to block, reject, disable, delete or change the management settings for any or all of the aforementioned technologies and/or other tracking, data aggregation and data analysis technologies, then certain areas of the Site might not function properly.

By visiting, accessing, registering with or using the Site, you acknowledge and agree in each instance that you are giving Outdoor Channel permission to monitor or otherwise track your activities on the Site, and that Outdoor Channel may use the aforementioned technologies and/or other tracking, data aggregation and data analysis technologies.

Additional information about how Outdoor Channel uses cookies and similar technologies and how you can change your settings are set forth in Outdoor Channel’s [Cookie Policy](http://www.outdoorchannel.com/content.aspx?id=64523).

### **4\. USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED.**

Outdoor Channel may use the personal and/or non-personal information it collects from you through the Site in a variety of ways, such as, for example, to:

  * Fulfill your requests;

  * Facilitate your movement through the Site;

  * Facilitate your use of the Site and/or its products and services;

  * Provide customer service;

  * Send you communications like, for example, administrative emails, newsletters, answers to your questions and updates about the Site;

  * Provide you with information about Outdoor Channel, its affiliated companies and/or their respective businesses, products and services by letter, email, text, telephone or other forms of communication;

  * Provide you with information about third-party businesses, products and/or services by letter, email, text, telephone or other forms of communication;

  * Improve the Site and/or its content, features and services;

  * Improve the products, services, marketing and/or promotional efforts of Outdoor Channel and/or its affiliated companies;

  * Create new products, services, marketing and/or promotions for Outdoor Channel and/or its affiliated companies;

  * Market the businesses, products and/or services of Outdoor Channel and/or its affiliated companies;

  * Help personalize user experiences with the Site and/or its products and services;

  * Analyze traffic to and through the Site;

  * Analyze user behavior and activity on or through the Site;

  * Conduct research and measurement activities for purposes of product and service research and development, advertising claim substantiation, market research, and other activities related to Outdoor Channel, its affiliated companies, the Site, and/or their respective products and/or services;

  * Monitor the activities of you and others on or through the Site;

  * Protect or enforce Outdoor Channel’s and/or its affiliated companies’ respective rights and properties; and/or

  * Protect or enforce the rights and properties of others (which may include you).

Outdoor Channel reserves the right to use your personal and non-personal information when:

  * Required by applicable law, court order or other governmental authority (including, without limitation and by way of example only, in response to a subpoena or other legal process); or

  * Outdoor Channel believes in good faith that such use is otherwise necessary or advisable (including, without limitation and by way of example only, to investigate, prevent, or take legal action against someone who may be causing injury to, interfering with, or threatening the rights, obligations or properties of Outdoor Channel, a user of the Site [which may include you], or anyone else who may be harmed by such activities or to further Outdoor Channel’s legitimate business interests).

### **5\. SHARING OF INFORMATION COLLECTED.**

Outdoor Channel reserves the right to share your personal information with Outdoor Channel’s employees, agents, administrators, accountants, financial advisors and legal advisors; with Outdoor Channel’s affiliated companies; and with those third parties who help manage, administer, monitor, distribute and/or operate the Site, and/or their respective products, services and/or features (e.g., web hosting companies, website administrators, mobile app distribution platforms, support services companies, data analysis companies, credit card or other payment processing companies, online shopping cart providers), as needed in order for them to perform such services.

Outdoor Channel does not limit the ways in which it may use or share non-personal information because non-personal information does not identify you. For example, Outdoor Channel may freely share non-personal information with its affiliated companies, its suppliers and its representatives, as well as with other individuals, businesses, and government entities.

You may choose to share certain information and/or follow other users on the Site. You may choose to share your contact information with other users or provide it publicly.

### **6\. DATA RETENTION.**

Outdoor Channel may retain your personal information and non-personal information for as long as it believes necessary. Outdoor Channel may dispose of or delete any such personal information or non-personal information at any time, except as set forth in any other agreement or document executed by both you and Outdoor Channel concerning the same or as required by law.

### **7\. TRANSACTIONS.**

In connection with any transaction that you conduct on, through or in relation to the Site, you may be asked to supply certain information relevant to the transaction, including, without limitation, your credit card number and expiration date, your billing address, your shipping address, your phone number and/or your email address. By submitting such information, you grant Outdoor Channel without charge the irrevocable, unencumbered, universe-wide and perpetual right to provide such information to third parties (e.g., payment processing companies, online shopping cart providers) for the purpose of facilitating the transaction.

### **8\. THIRD PARTY APPLICATIONS AND NETWORKS.**

The Site, and/or any communications sent through or as a function of the Site may contain links to third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers and/or applications. Third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers and/or applications may also contain links to the Site. TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, OUTDOOR CHANNEL IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR, AND YOU HEREBY RELEASE OUTDOOR CHANNEL FROM ANY AND ALL LIABILITY WHICH MAY ARISE FROM, SUCH THIRD PARTY WEBSITES, NETWORKS, PLATFORMS, SERVERS AND APPLICATIONS (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE PRIVACY POLICIES AND PRACTICES OF SUCH THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES, NETWORKS, PLATFORMS, SERVERS, AND APPLICATIONS).

You may have the opportunity to access the Site using your online user accounts with certain third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications, which may be subject to separate privacy policies pertaining to those third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications. Outdoor Channel may also collect information from those third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications (such as, for example, your name, your personal interests, when you “like” or click links provided by or through those third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers, or applications, and other information available through your online account or page with those third-party websites, networks, platforms, servers or applications). IT IS YOUR RESPONSIBILITY TO CAREFULLY READ, ACCEPT AND COMPLY WITH THE RELEVANT TERMS OF USE, WAIVERS, AND PRIVACY POLICIES ASSOCIATED WITH THOSE THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES, NETWORKS, PLATFORMS, SERVERS AND APPLICATIONS.

### **9\. SECURITY.**

Outdoor Channel implements security measures to help protect the personal information it collects through the Site. For example, Outdoor Channel encrypts the transmission of certain information through the Site by using secure socket layer (SSL) technology.

REGARDLESS OF THE FOREGOING, PLEASE OBSERVE THAT “PERFECT” OR “100%” SECURITY DOES NOT EXIST ON THE INTERNET. THEREFORE, YOUR ACCESS AND USE OF THE SITE, AND YOUR OPENING OF ANY COMMUNICATIONS SENT THROUGH OR AS A FUNCTION OF THE SITE ARE DONE AT YOUR OWN RISK.

### **10\. RETENTION, REVIEW, AND CHANGE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED.**

You may request at any time that Outdoor Channel provide you with an opportunity to review and change your personal information collected through the Site, if any, or to no longer use your personal information to provide you with any products or services. Please submit any such request (“Request Concerning Personal Information”) to [info@outdoorchannel.com](mailto:info@outdoorchannel.com), with a subject line of “Your Personal Information.”

For each Request Concerning Personal Information, please state “Your Personal Information” in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:

  1. the nature of your request;

  2. that the request is related to “Your Personal Information;”

  3. your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address; and

  4. whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

Outdoor Channel is not responsible for any Request Concerning Personal Information that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled or incorrectly sent.

You are solely responsible for the accuracy and content of your personal information, and for keeping your personal information current and correct.

### **11.YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS.**

If you are a resident of the State of California and Outdoor Channel has an established business relationship with you, then, pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, you have the right to request the following at any time: (a) information from Outdoor Channel free of charge regarding the manner in which Outdoor Channel shares certain personal information collected through the Site with third parties who use such information for direct marketing purposes; and (b) the discontinuation (or opt-out) of Outdoor Channel’s sharing of such information with such third parties. Please submit any such request ( _ **California Privacy Rights Request**_ ) to [info@outdoorchannel.com](mailto:info@outdoorchannel.com), with a subject line of “Your California Privacy Rights.”

For each _**California Privacy Rights Request**_ , please state “Your California Privacy Rights” in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:

  1. the nature of your request;

  2. that the request is related to “Your California Privacy Rights;”

  3. your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address; and

  4. whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

Outdoor Channel is not responsible for a _**California Privacy Rights Request**_ that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled or incorrectly sent.

You are solely responsible for the accuracy and content of your personal information, and for keeping your personal information current and correct.

Further, Outdoor Channel does not respond to “do not track” (DNT) signals.

Finally, as explained further above, Outdoor Channel does not authorize third parties to collect your personal information when you use the Site, except as expressly stated in this Privacy Policy. TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, OUTDOOR CHANNEL IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR, AND YOU HEREBY RELEASE OUTDOOR CHANNEL FROM ANY AND ALL LIABILITY WHICH MAY ARISE FROM, SUCH THIRD PARTIES’ UNAUTHORIZED COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.

### **12\. MODIFICATIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

OUTDOOR CHANNEL MAY SUPPLEMENT, AMEND, OR OTHERWISE MODIFY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AT ANY TIME WITHOUT NOTICE TO YOU. SUCH SUPPLEMENTS, AMENDMENTS AND OTHER MODIFICATIONS WILL BE POSTED ON THIS OR A SIMILAR PAGE OF THE SITE, AND SHALL BE DEEMED EFFECTIVE AS OF THEIR STATED EFFECTIVE OR MODIFICATION DATE. IT IS YOUR RESPONSIBILITY TO CAREFULLY REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY EACH TIME YOU VISIT, ACCESS, REGISTER WITH OR USE THE SITE.

AGAIN, BY VISITING, ACCESSING, REGISTERING WITH OR USING THE SITE, YOU ARE AUTOMATICALLY ACCEPTING AND AGREEING TO THE MOST-RECENT VERSION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AS WELL AS THE MOST-RECENT VERSION OF THE SITE’S [TERMS OF SERVICE](http://www.outdoorchannel.com/termsofuse), AND YOUR CONTINUING VISIT, ACCESS, REGISTRATION WITH OR USE OF THE SITE REAFFIRMS YOUR ACCEPTANCE AND AGREEMENT IN EACH INSTANCE.

### **13\. SEVERABILITY.**

If any term or condition of this Privacy Policy is deemed invalid or unenforceable by a court of law with binding authority, then the remaining terms and conditions shall not be affected, and the court shall reform the invalidated or unenforceable term or condition to the maximum extent permitted under the law and consistent with the intent of this Privacy Policy.

### **14\. CONTACT US.**

Please direct any questions you may have about this Privacy Policy to [info@outdoorchannel.com](mailto:info@outdoorchannel.com), with a subject line of “Privacy Policy.”

The foregoing contact information may change from time-to-time by supplementation, amendment, or modification of this Privacy Policy.

### **15\. INTERNATIONAL USERS.**

For any of the above purposes and in view of Outdoor Channel’s global operations, you agree that Outdoor Channel may transfer some or all of your personal information, your non-personal information and/or other data to countries outside your resident jurisdiction, and may process and/or store such information in the United States of America. You agree and recognize that countries outside of your jurisdiction may not have as comprehensive data protection laws as those existing in your resident jurisdiction. For more information please contact Outdoor Channel in the manner described in _section 14_ above.

### **16\. MODIFICATION DATE.**

This Privacy Policy was last modified on January 17, 2018.
